#### PROFILE:

Innovative and collaborative Designer with 23 years of experience focused on the apparel industry (18 years in NYC)

An inspired team player with proven abilities to lead all phases of the design process and problem solve. Demonstrated sucess of working in companies of various sizes and across differing marketing strategies.

Strength in design and developing contemporary both Missy and Plus design in both Knit & Woven Tops, Dresses and Bottoms.

Creative strength including Trend analysis, Maket Research, Color, Fabric development and Garment Construction.

# CONTACT:

Phone: 347. 852. 1517 Email:oliviaypark113@gmail.com

#### EDUCATION:

FASHION INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY NEW YORK, NY 2002

Associate's Degree in Fashion Design, GPA 3.75, Graduated Cum Laude

KYUNG HEE UNVERSITY, Seoul, Korea 1997

BS, Fashion Design, GPA 3.5

PORTFOLIO AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST

# Olivia Youngmee Park

SENIOR DESIGNER/MERCHANDISER

# EXPERIENCE

#### DESIGN CONSULTANT FOR ACTIVEWEAR COMPANY

July 2019-Mar 2020

- Designed and developed women's active wear for company in startup mode
- Provided market research and consulted on design details for seasonal sales samples
- Created techinical packages including sketches, trims, colors and garment details
- Attended fittings and managed oversea suppliers to ensure accuracy of production
- Created comprehensive, precise linesheets to present product details to customers

#### ES SUTTON, NEW YORK, NY

July 2014-Sept 2019

# Senior Designer (Contemporary Missy and Plus Size Department)

- Managed entire product design process to include colors, fabric, art direction trim, sketching, CAD and fits as pertains to styling
- Oversaw for all market research and trend analysis to identify new trends fabric and seasonal concept
- Sourced fabric and developed seasonal samples for presentations
- Responsible for approving fabric quality, strike offs, colors and trims for production
- Provided recommendations regarding seasonal themes, edits to line and new concepts
   Ensure that product is consistent with market trends as well as business strategy

# **Delivered Results**

- Designed and created elevated fashion tops and dresses
- Generated 3 million incremental unit in sales into Walmart stores over four year period
- Launched fashion tops, dresses and jumpsuit category that generates an average 450,000 units of business each season
- Designed and developed a number of garments that have been featured on national magazine and catalogue covers

#### SPORT ELLE, NEW YORK, NY

Aug 2012-May 2014

# Senior Designer (Contemporary Missy Sportswear and Active Wear)

- Worked with head of design to achive over all product strategy
- Shopped Stores for inspirations and research market trends
- Selected styles, fabrics, trims and colors that fit into items and groupings
- Executed detailed development tech pack including embellishment layout
- Communicated and followed up with overseas office for all development samples
- Attended fittings and worked with tech designer to endure fits and procuct quality
- Appoved trims, embellishment and layouts for production
- Mentored and managed assistant designer to foster design team effectively

#### **Delivered Results**

- Designed and created elevated fashion knit, woven tops and oversaw the development of new line of activewear that contributed incremental sales growth in the division
- Enhanced sales growth each season by an average of 11% through the addition of new innovative and trendy designs

# TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop

Proficient with all Micosoft Office Suite Software

Garment construction & details

**Technical Pacakges** 

Sketching

Drapings

Fittings

Fabric Development

Market Analysis

### LANGUAGES:

**ENGLISH** 

**KOREAN** 

#### REFERENCE:

Roberta Mcalice Senior Knitwear Designer ES Sutton rmcalice@optonline.net 203-246-0636

Spencer Lee Senior Graphic Designer ES Sutton spencelee@gmail.com 646-325-7642

Shanon Kwon
Production Director
By Design LLC.
shanonskwon@gmail.com
201-856-9670

#### EXPERIENCE-

### THE JONES GROUP, NEW YORK, NY

Feb 2009-May 2012

Sweater and Knit Cut & Sew Designer - JONES NEW YORK SIGNATURE

- Generated detailed hand/illustrator sketches and technical pacakages
- Responsible for all operational aspects of product development, from sales sample to final product, to ensure top-quality fullfilment of client's orders
- Performed thorough market research for seasonal concepts, yarn and knit-down developments
- Updated all design boards and sketches into PLM system
- Played key role in creating design concept boards and design product based on seasonal concepts

#### THE JONES GROUP, NEW YORK, NY

Aug 2006-Feb 2009

#### **Knitwear Designer-JONES WEAR STUDIO**

- Created meticulous flat sketches and technical pacakges
- Attended fit meetings and collaborated with team of four technical designers to ensure product quality
- Researched market for trends in style, color, yarn and trims as part of presentation to executive management team on seasonal collection

#### BY DESIGN LLC, NEW YORK, NY

Jun 2003-Jun 2006

# Associate Knitwear Designer- Love By Design Both Junior and Missy

- Produced all design layouts and technical pacakges for overseas vendors
- Conducted market research for design inspirations, yarns/fabrics, silhouettes and color
- Participated in all fit sessions and recorded detailed fit notes to communicate to factories

#### LI & FUNG, Seoul, Korea

Sept 2000-Jun 2001

#### Cut & Sew Knitwer Technical Designer - American Eagles Outfitters

- Provided guidance to vendors in order to execute on all Cut & Sew proto samples
- Checked and ensure on all measurement and pattern of bulk fits
- Communicated with overseas buyer for fit comments

#### CARTE KNIT APPAREL, Seoul, Korea

July 1997-Sept 2000

Knitwear Designer - Carte Knit Label (High End Ladies Contemporary label in Korea)

- Designed and followed up in all design phases of high end and Missy Sweater labels
- Researched domestic and global market in order to identify trend and styles
- Traveled to Europe and Japan for market research and sample shopping
- Communicated with domestic vendors for entire design process to include yarn, color, artwork and trims
- Fit modeled to try on all new development samples and gave feed backs to ensure fits and details into style
- Worked with Design Director to create concept board and seasonal presentations